I'm looking at a piece in front of me.
This is from a while ago, but
it's you discussing long-held dogma that
ends up being unviable. So, for
instance, the common-held belief after
PayPal's sale to eBay that fraud will
kill you in the payment space, right?
>> Yeah. And I'm wondering how you orient
yourself as an investor to
stress test
those types of dogma. It's really hard
because you often end up You start out
with some set of beliefs. You think
something's interesting.
Or maybe you invest in it, maybe you
start a company in it.
And then it turns out the thing you
think is really interesting turns out to
be really hard and you get killed.
And then 5 years later a company comes
up that actually does it and wins. Mhm.
And the question is why? Why did the
thing suddenly work when it didn't
before? Or there's 10 attempts to do X
and then
suddenly is it that technology got good
enough? It could be a regulatory change.
It could be a market shift. It could be
whatever. An example be Harvey AI Legal
where selling to law firms traditionally
has been awful.
And Harvey's not much broader than that,
right? They also have very strong
enterprise adoption and
lots of different people using them in
different ways, but the dogma was always
like building stuff for law firms is
crappy as a business and you should
never do it. But what AI did is it
shifted things from selling tools to
selling work product or selling units of
labor. That's really the shift in
generative AI.
We're going from seats and we're going
from software
and SaaS and we're moving into a world
where we're selling human labor
equivalents. We're selling work hours or
labor hours or whatever you want to call
it. Mhm. of cognition. And so, Harvey is
effectively helping really augment
lawyers in different ways. And part of
that's a knowledge corpus, but a lot of
it is this tooling that really helps
lawyers achieve the goals that they have
in different ways in a collaborative
manner in some cases. And so, this is a
fundamentally different type of product
from what people were selling before.
And so, it opened up the market in a way
that the market wasn't open before.
There's actually a broader conversation
around is the world market limited or
founder limited in terms of
entrepreneurial success. The Y
Combinator school of thought is that we
just don't have enough founders, and if
we had 10 times as many founders, we'd
have 10 times as many big companies.
And there's an alternate school of
thought, which is how many markets are
actually open in any given moment in
time, and those are the ones where you
can build big companies. Cuz if the
market isn't open to innovation or
change or whatever or hasn't is
undergoing a shift, you can't really
build anything or anyhow, so why do it?
And the striking thing about AI is it's
opened up tons and tons of markets that
were closed for a long time.
And it's opened it up because of
capabilities, but it's also opened it up
because every CEO is asking themselves,
"What's my AI story?"
And there's way more openness to try
things than I've ever seen in my life.
And so,
we have this odd moment in time where
things are massively available for
founders to do new things.
And if you're an AI company and you're
not seeing explosive growth quickly,
something's fundamentally broken.
Because the markets are so open
that you can suddenly grow at a rate
that you've never grown before. There's
always been cases of companies that just
go like this.
But again, you look at the ramps of
OpenAI and Anthropic, and it's the
fastest ramps to tens of billions ever.
Percentages of GDP, it's like crazy. If
we come back to your comment of
not necessarily market first and
strength of team second all the time,
but like you said, you 90% agree with
that, right? And
if you have an excellent team in a
terrible market, like that's going to be
that's going to be a difficult one to
execute. How do you determine what is a
good versus great market or just what is
a great market? What do you look for?
And the example you gave, I might be
overreading this, but what you said that
when Google shut down, I think it was
Maven, right? That's an interesting kind
of event-based approach as an input to
investing, right? Cuz you're like,
"Okay, if they're not going to build it,
we're
that suddenly creates
a playing field for
startups. Yeah. to play in that space.
So, could you speak to more
of how you determine or look for great
markets? I mean, there's a few different
ways to think about it. One is like,
some people take the framework of why
now. What's shifted now that makes it
something interesting market because
people have been trying to do things for
a long time in every market. And so,
that may be a regulatory shift, right?
Some Sara, the fleet management company
benefited from the fact that somebody
was regulation around needing in-cab
monitoring of drivers. So, you had some
of the cameras watching people so they
don't fall asleep while they're driving
trucks on the road, right? Mhm. And so,
that was their entry point to that start
building out a suite of software.
But, it was a regulatory shift.
Sometimes there's technology shifts,
like what's happening in AI. And the
crazy thing about the AI shift is
the foundation models instantly plugged
into a massive set of markets, which is
basically all enterprise data and
information and email and just all white
collar work was suddenly available to
AI. Mhm. Cuz it was the perfect market
for that. It also plugged into code,
which is a type of white collar work.
So, it's just suddenly it just inserts
into language and language is used
everywhere in in enterprises as well as
in consumer. And so, there's just a
massive market to tap into and transform
or set of markets. Robotics is a little
bit different from that because even if
you had the world's best robotic model,
the submarkets that already have robotic
hardware are quite small on a relative
basis.
And so, you don't have that instant
runway that you would with
language unless you come up with
something new there. That's kind of an
aside that I think robotics is really
interesting and be important. It's more
just that nuance of like what's that
instant thing you plug into
commercially. And then,
there's regulatory shifts and technology
shifts, there's
incumbency or company shifts,
competitive shifts.
A company may blow itself up, it may get
bought by a competitor. One company I'm
I'm excited about on the security side
is called In-Q-Tel and they're basically
competing in part with Hashi. Hashi got
bought by IBM. Anytime you get bought by
IBM, you slow you slow down a lot
usually. Mhm. Suddenly it creates more
opportunity for a startup. So, I I feel
like there are these different things
that can change at a given moment in
time. Mhm. [clears throat] It could be
the market trying really fast as
Coinbase and crypto, right? You just
have suddenly this adoption and
proliferation of token types. There's
lots and lots and lots of different
markets that are interesting. The
commonality is usually like is it also
big? Is there a big enough town? And
there's two types of towns. There's fake
town. Just for people listening who
might not have it. Your total
addressable market.
>> Total addressable market. So what's the
market you're in?
And sometimes people come up with these
fake markets. They're like, oh well,
we are facilitating
global e-commerce and global e-commerce,
I'm making up the number is $30 a year
and so we're in a $30 a year market and
if we get just a tenth of a percent of
that is 300 billion of revenue and
you're like, that's not
that's not your market. Your market is
like you built this little optimization
engine for SMB websites or whatever.
That's not a $30
market. And so really it's kind of
defining the market. There's a really
famous example of this where defining
your market changes how you think about
it.
And so that was Coca-Cola, right? So
Coke and Pepsi were roughly neck and
neck in terms of market share
for decades.
And then one of the Coke CEO said, hey,
maybe we should be thinking about our
share as share of
liquid sold.
Like drinks, not share of soda.
And so we just went from 50% market
share to 0.5%.
And that's why they bought Dasani and
that's why they entered all these other
markets, right? Because they said,
our definition of our market is wrong.
>> Mhm. We're not in the soda pop business,
we're in the drinks business. And so I
think also conceptualizing what you're
doing can really help change
your scope of ambition or how you think
about what you're doing. If you're
trying to spot
along the lines of the fraud kill you in
the payment space, right? Any
dogma in the AI world, the sphere of AI,
right?
Anything anything hopped to mind where
you think, uh, maybe that's not true now
or maybe in like two years it'll be
completely untrue, but people will have
latched onto this belief as
one of the thou shalt not or thou thou
shall
commandments. I don't know. I mean,
there's some things that have circulated
in the past around what's the ROI on the
capex spend of that and whatever be paid
back and I just like
I think that stuff is probably off. But
yeah, I think fundamentally there are
moments in time where it's very smart to
be contrarian. And there are moments in
time where being consensus is the
smartest possible thing you can do. And
I think right now we're in a moment in
time where being consensus is very
right.
You know, and you can really overthink
it and what's the contrarian thing? We
should go do a bunch of hardware stuff
cuz blah blah blah. And like maybe just
buy more AI. You know what I mean? I
think people make these things way too
complicated.